

DAMIAN VATHER

DATA SCIENTIST

PERSONAL PROFILE

Showcasing the power of data driven decision making, by bringing the core principles of machine learning into the market, that will improve business performance.

Utilizing the nature evolved learning techniques to learn from the experiences of human and machine interactions and to better understand language, recognize speech and classify & identify visual inputs.

Developing products focussed on delivering an authentic, personalized and relevant experiences and interactions to compliment human intelligence and improve human level performances putting customer at the center of the organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Dashboarding (Power BI & Tableau)
- Database Management (SQL)
- Python
- Java
- Streamlit
- AWS cloud computing
- Microsoft office
- HTML and LaTex
- C++ and sharp

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Head of Part-Time Delivery

EXPLORE Data Science Academy (2021 - Present)

Responsible for the success of operations within the academy.

- Management of stakeholders and reporting at regular intervals
- Coordination of delivery teams
- Ensuring student success by curating their learning journeys
- Analysis of student performance for insight into the path students take and how we can improve on it
- Constant research on how to improve alternative methods of education
- Project management/technical lead on special projects

Data Scientist

EXPLORE Data Science Academy (2020 - 2021)

Head Instructor and Coordinator

- webinar creation and delivery
- content development and review
- technical lead for project teams
- course administration
- lecturing and tutoring
- coordination of various corporate projects

Junior Data Scientist

EXPLORE Data Science Academy (2019-2020)

Explore AI

Data Science consultant for Thames Water United Kingdom Developed:

- Enhancing data systems
- Improving data visualisations
- Automated anomaly detections
- Automated system validation
- BI development

Explore Academy

Head Instructor and Supervisor of the Data Science course

- Content Creation
- Webinar Creation and Delivery
- Online Tutoring and Lecturing
- Online course Facilitator
- Technical Lead of data science intern project teams within corporate companies

SOFT SKILLS

- Diligent
- Driven
- Team leader
- Communicator
- Creative
- Critical thinking

HOBBIES

- Karate
- Playing Sport
- Family time
- Fishing
- Outdoors
- Gaming
- Education

CONTACT INFORMATION

Cell:

0814295220

Email

damian.vather@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/damianvather/

Github:

https://github.com/damian-vather

EDUCATION

Bachelors Computer Science

University of South Africa (2020-current)

Data Science Qualification

Explore Software (2018-2018)

Bachelors Civil Engineering (Year 1 & 2)

University of Johannesburg (2015-2017)

Matric Certificate

Randpark Highschool (2010-2015)

PROJECTS

- Eskom | Implement the "extract, transform, load" (ETL) framework to analyse and present insights on Eskom and South Africa's Energy Landscape.
- Zindi | Sendy Logistics Challenge: Build a machine learning model that will predict an accurate time of arrival for motorbike deliveries from the pickup point to the destination. The regression model was deployed within a web-based API, using Flask.
- Kaggle | Climate Change Belief Analysis: Build a classification model that is able to classify whether or not a person believes in climate change, based on their novel tweet data. The model was deployed using Streamlit's and hosted on an AWS EC2 instance.
- Zindi | To Vaccinate or Not to Vaccinate: It's not a Question Challenge: Develop a machine learning model to assess if a Twitter post related to vaccinations is positive, neutral, or negative.
- Kaggle | EDSA Movie Recommendation Challenge: Build a recommendation algorithm that predicts how a user will rate a movie they have not viewed, based on their historical preferences.
- Covid 19 Predictive modelling and data insight dashboard.
 Currently use an api to populate dashboard with live data and a python notebook to forecast daily cases.
- Nedbank | Client product optimisation using advanced machine learning tools to predict the next best product for a customer